Never forget why you are the church.
Romans chapter 12.
Before we get any further here,
I want to do something real quick, and I need your
full participation and honesty.
everyone, if you're willing to do that, say amen.
Okay, everyone else, you just hang tight.
Um, I want everyone right
now to bow your heads and close your eyes.
Okay?
I don't want anyone looking around.
I want this to be something.
Just follow my lead on this, okay?
Please trust me in this, okay?
If you're here this morning,
And maybe you have something in your life that is causing you Pain,
suffering, grief.
Maybe there's a situation or circumstance in your life that you're
just, you feel like you don't know what to do, you don't know how
to handle it.
Maybe there's some decisions, that you have in your life,
that you're just looking for counsel, and you feel like you can't get it, whether it's
a career move or a financial move or just
whatever decision it could be.
Maybe you have a sickness or disease that you're dealing with.
If there's something in your life.
That is just simply difficult.
For whatever reason, it's just difficult.
It's causing difficult times for you.
But everyone, I don't want anyone looking around here.
Can you just raise your hand?
I want you to keep it raised.
Okay, now, I told you, Paul, I'm a lead.
everyone, keep your hands raised, please.
I want everyone to look up now and look around the room.
Okay, you can put your hands down.
I want you to remember that.
for later on in the message.
Because as I was standing there and worshiping
with my church family, I just had a feeling that,
man, we just got some people that are going through some stuff.
And sometimes I get up here and I feel that barrier
and I, and I, it makes me angry and I say things like, God break
the wall down or break the barriers that will, and it
kind of comes off as very aggressive and, but, but not
where God had me and had me this morning.
It was more of a compassion thing of like, man, we're going through some stuff together.
You may not feel like it's together, but God did not design us
or you, me or you to go through these kind of things alone.
So I want you to think about what you just saw.
And I don't want to, if you didn't raise your hand, I'm not trying to shame
you anything like that, but there's something in your life you could have raised your hand for.
So this morning we're going to continue right along.
With the theme in mind of the impact of the gospel, we are looking at how it
affects us in our relationships with others.
A truth from last week is something that we need not forget.
Your personal walk with Christ impacts those around you.
In a culture that pushes selfish living, promotes
a life that is all about you and no one else, teaches
us that to only about how to get ahead, no matter
the cost, make sure that you take care of yourself, over everyone else.
Church, you do realize this is the exact same
way Satan tempted Eve and talked her into eating
of the tree of the knowledge of good and evil.
He convinced her that God's commandment
was causing her to miss out on her potential in life.
You see, I don't understand what you're saying.
If you go all the way back to Genesis chapter 3, starting
in verse one, this is a very familiar story to many of you.
Maybe it's not familiar to you, just listen to it.
It says this.
Now the serpent was more subtle than any beast of the field
which the Lord God had made.
And he sent it to the woman, yea, hath God said, ye shall not
eat of every tree of the garden.
And the woman said unto the serpent, we may eat of the tree of
the fruit of the trees of the garden, but of the fruit of the tree, which
is in the midst of the garden.
God has said, ye shall not eat of it, neither shall ye
touch it, lest ye die.
And the servant said unto the woman, You shall not surely die.
For God does know that in
a day that ye eat thereof, then your eyes shall be opened,
and ye shall be as gods.
Notice little G there, because no one is like big G God, amen?
Knowing good and evil.
And when the woman saw that the tree was good for food.
And then it was pleasant to the eyes.
And a tree to be desired to make one wise.
She took of the fruit thereof and did eat and gave also unto her husband with her.
And he did eat.
So in other words, what happened here is The serpent.
The conniving, wicked, sinful, fallen serpent.
Convinced Adam and Eve to question God's plan for their life.
That's not what God said.
God's holding back on you, Eve.
I know what's better for you, Eve.
Notice he really, he took some truth and constorted
it to where it was more of a lie.
He said, hey, God knows that when you eat of this fruit, your eyes will be opened.
What happened the moment they ate of it?
They realized they were naked.
And in shame they covered up.
He told them what would happen.
Can I tell you something?
The enemy in this world?
Loves to tell you a little truth, but a lot of lie.
He's been doing it and spreading the same lives since
this occasion in the Bible.
Why would he not change it up?
He doesn't have to.
It still works.
See, we need to understand that God's commandments to us found
in scripture are not to hurt us or to
keep us from thriving.
It's the exact opposite, which is true.
His commandments help us and protect us
and offer us a life that without them we could not achieve.
The reason why I'm talking so much about his commandments is that people get
this idea, well, when you talk about commandments,
it's all it's all about the Ten Commandments.
And the funny thing is this, they don't even know what they're saying because if you really truly
follow the Ten Commandments, your relationship with God will be protected
and your relationship with others will be protected.
Amen?
And so, but there's so much more in God's word than just that.
That is a foundation, but we didn't know all of it.
See, the scriptures are jam-packed full of commandments that God gives us for
our benefit and the benefit of those around us.
And that is what we are looking at and studying here in this
portion of Romans 12.
It is a string of commandments for us to live
and to obey.
So far, we have looked at Romans 12, verse 9 through
12, if you're there, say read.
Oh, okay.
If you're there, say read.
Let love be without the simulation, that means hypocrisy.
And pour that which is evil cleeds that which is good.
Be kindly affectionate one to another with brotherly love, in
order, preferring one another, not slothful
in business, fervent in spirit, serving the Lord, rejoicing in hope.
This morning, we're going to continue by finishing up or at least continuing
Romans 12 verse 12.
says this, patient and tribulation.
Continuing instant in prayer.
If you'd like a title to have it,
I apologize, I didn't make a title slide.
I forgot about that.
I just added it, but it's a biblical response to difficult times.
Oh, there it is.
Never mind.
I just, I just surprised myself there.
Thank you, RV team.
A biblical response to difficult times.
Let's pray.
Father we, thank you, Lord.
God will just ask you, Lord, that God, you speak to us.
God minister to us.
God comfort us through your Holy Spirit.
God is a humbling.
sobering and heartbreaking truth.
God has so many suffering here.
There's so many that are in difficult circumstances and situations that are hard.
So, Lord, God, I pray that we can respond biblically to those times.
God, I pray that we understand that your word is for us, not against
us, because you are forced and not against us.
So Lord, speak through me, God.
God, allow me to freely minister to my people.
And in Jesus name, pray.
Amen.
Last week we looked at the 2 main words of the text, rejoicing and hope.
Now, we can rejoice, that is to be glad and happy because we
expect that God is going to do what he says that he is going to do.
Again, I want to just remind you over and over again.
As a believer, you are to be joyful.
Yes, that's the foundation.
That never goes anywhere.
But you know God expects us to also be happy and glad.
God never saved us to be sour faced
and irritated and this and that and walking in and if
people do this when you walk in, uh-oh.
Right?
That's not the person, that's probably your attitude.
So we got to understand.
God expects us to rejoice.
That is to be happy, to be glad, to have the joy of
the Lord, no matter the circumstance.
Why?
Because we expect him to do his work.
We expect his will to be fulfilled.
We are promised this in scripture, 2nd Corinthians 98, and
God is able to make all grace abound to you, so that
always having all sufficiency in everything.
You may have abundance for every good deed.
Philippians 419, and my God will supply all
your needs according to his riches in glory in Christ Jesus.
David wrote about this in Psalm 235.
Listen, if anybody knew what it meant to be sad and
depressed and anxious and all the things that come with this
world and have enemies all around you.
It was King David.
Look at what he said.
Thou preparest a table before me.
In the presence of mine enemies.
Thou anointest my head with oil.
My cup runneth over.
Church, our hope is not a shaky hope.
It's not a skeptical hope.
Our hope is fixing the promises of God through Christ Jesus.
We can expect him to meet our needs.
Listen, the world hopes very differently than we do.
Parents in the room, have you ever hoped that your kids brush their teeth?
That's a shaky hope, amen?
Right?
They're already in bed.
They're already tucked in.
You were busy, so you didn't, you didn't get the time to like
force them to the bathroom and had the 15 minutes of crying
and screaming to get their teeth brushed.
I don't know if that's if that happens in your house, but it happens in my house sometimes.
And so and so you don't do that.
So you just kind of, you know, you hope, well, I hope they did what they're supposed to do.
And so you get in the bed, you tuck them in, you do the Bible's thing, you do
the prayer thing, you put the sound machine on, you do all the little
night lights, everything, man.
It's like a, you know, 2.5 hour process, and then you sit
there and you say, okay, now, sweetheart, you brush your teeth, right?
And they're like, were we supposed to do that?
Well, what do you gotta do?
And you got to get them out of bed, right?
You gotta do all the things.
Turn the lights on, it starts over.
Listen, that's not the way we hope.
I know that sounds so silly.
But when the world hopes, they're hoping because they feel like it could not happen.
Well, I hope I get that job.
Well, I hope that I can do this.
I hope that I can do that.
See, understand something.
When we hope in Jesus Christ, when we hope according to
his promises, not necessarily our plans, we can have full
faith that what he says is going to come to fruition.
And that's a beautiful hope right there.
Amen.
Now, the rest of this verse, if you remember saying, amen.
I think that I don't know who put energy is caffeine
in my little drink right there, but it worked.
Amen.
I'm feeling a lot better.
So we're going to continue this and it runs right through the same thread here.
And when to look at the 1st part, it says this.
Romans 12, rejoicing in hope.
You see 3 more words.
Patient in tribulation.
We're going to do the same thing as we expose the truth of these commandments for our life.
So we're going to look at the 1st word we see here.
We see the word patient.
Depending on the translation you use, you might see the word perseverance here.
Now this word means in the Greek to resist.
Stand firm by holding one's ground.
So think about it for a second.
We ought to be patient.
That is persevering.
That means we are to resist and stand firm by
holding our ground.
Do you realize this?
Nothing and no one can take anything from us that we do not 1st offer them.
When it comes to the things that are most important.
The things of eternity, the things of God.
Nothing can ever take anything away from you that God has given you.
See, Adam and Eve had the entire garden to themselves.
I mean, listen, I don't know what it looked like.
I know that there's TV shows and movies and pieces
of art that we try to even fathom what the garner of eat,
eat and could look like, and we have no idea.
It had to be good though.
It had to been awesome.
But see, understand this.
They had need for nothing.
They were in complete fellowship with God.
But they gave up ground to the enemy.
Now, what was Isoda giving up ground?
Well, this is a really good physical representation.
They were kicked out of the garden.
They had to go.
And from that point on, life got a lot tougher.
Again, I don't have time to go through all of it, but they they
gave up ground to the enemy.
They could have resisted.
They could have stood their ground.
You say, well, maybe Eve didn't know.
No, Eve did know.
Listen, all Eve had to say is exactly what you had to say in situation and temptation.
That's not what God said.
This is what God said.
I'm not standing upon what you say, devil.
I'm not standing upon what you say, world.
I'm standing upon a solid rock of ages.
That's Jesus Christ.
What he says goes in my life.
And anything contrary, I'm not gonna listen to it.
Amen.
So we see here, they gave up ground.
They were cast out of that perfect garden.
Now understand that in order to resist, there has to be something to resist.
It's not resisting where there is no opposition.
That brings us to our next word.
Tribulation.
Patient in tribulation.
Now, what does this word mean?
Well, in the Greek, it means trouble.
Tribulation?
oppression, but here's what I want to focus on right here.
Trouble or affliction that causes look at it.
pressure.
Trouble or affliction.
that causes pressure.
I want you to hear this truth, how you respond to pressure,
says much about your spiritual preparedness.
Because understand something to you.
Pressure is going to come.
From all angles, pressure is going to come.
We do not get the luxury of being exempt from trials and tribulations of this world.
We live in a sinful phone world.
We are in a battle the moment our feet hit the ground and it never stops.
Our adversary knows what it'll take to get us.
It's constant pressure applied.
Think about it.
What makes the head code so miserable?
Anyone ever had a head cold?
It's so funny what y'all relate to, what y'all don't relate to, right?
I'll say something and be like, oh, I don't know what the TV is.
And the head coats are like, yeah, I have one right now.
It's just insane.
But listen, I've had head codes, right?
I haven't had one in a long time.
Uh, anyway, I'm not gonna, I'm not even gonna go there.
I take this thing.
It's a little supplement.
I not going to say the word.
Whatever ADHD one more time.
I'm sorry.
But no, you've had a head cold.
Right?
What's so bad about a head cold?
Well, if you think about it, have you ever heard someone say to you when you have a head code,
it's just a head code.
You heard that?
It's just a head code.
What you complaining about?
It's just the head color.
Why are you stopping?
It's just a head code.
Well, here's the thing.
For the most part, I do think functionally.
A head code just at itself should not stop you from doing stuff.
But here's the thing.
You may have some drainage.
You might even have a cough, but the worst part of a head code is
the pressure that seems to never go away.
Y'all know what I'm talking about?
Now, if you're like me, I don't like being sick.
I, the cliche
of men being big babies when they're sick, you
could write a book and put me in it, okay?
Like, that's me, all right?
Heather, she'll have like the flu.
She'll have like Ebola.
She'll have all these things and she'll just be walking around just
taking care of the kids and doing all things and I
get a code and I'm in bed like, I mean, I'm about to see Jesus.
You understand what I'm saying?
Like, get me some pedia light.
I'm dying.
But listen, with the head coach, it's constant pressure.
If you're like me, that constant pressure, sometimes you
may not be able to relate, but it kind of caused me to panic a little bit.
Like, when is this going to go away?
Like, I can't handle this anymore.
This has got to stop.
And so what happens when that happens?
Now just bear with me.
Well, you start lashing out, your actions, your words,
become the contingent on that pressure that you're getting.
The pressure creates actions that
would not otherwise be taken if the pressure was not there.
I can't say that again if I tried.
Amen?
But here's the thing.
The world in the same way applies
constant pressure to the believer.
And it cannot come as a surprise.
We must be prepared.
Now, do we see this in scripture?
You're saying, man, you're talking about head calls and all this stuff?
What are you talking about?
Well, we actually do see this in scripture.
There's a man, a young man named Joseph.
Now, we were introduced to him all the way back in Genesis 37.
As a matter of fact, chapters 37 through
50 of the book of Genesis, which is a big book, right,
are basically committed to the story of this young man.
When he was just a young man 17 years old, God
gave him a dream that would cause his brothers to despise him.
Not to give you all the details, but it's basically, hey, you're going to bow down
to me, and it's going to be awesome and great.
And he was like the 2nd young.
And they're like, bro, what you mean?
Because in that time age was a big deal.
Like, you know, younger brothers didn't talk to older brothers like that.
And he even said, hey, mom, dad, you're gonna bow down to me.
And they're like, you're crazy, dude.
don't like you.
And literally, they began to hate him from that day.
And so to make matters worse, he was his father's favorite.
His father being Jacob, who wrestled with God, changed his name to Israel, right?
Israel, 12 sons.
tribes, nation of Israel.
Okay, anyway, just trying to connect it all for you.
It was so bad, they plotted against him and eventually
trapped him in a pit and sold him into slavery.
Now, I don't know about you, but that seems like some worldly tribulation, amen?
I'm not been in a, I don't know if I've ever been in a pit, but I don't think I'd like it.
I think that the pressure had begun in his life.
Now, remember, God sent him the dream.
The scripture is very clear that God gave him that dream.
Now, how he handled that dream.
he could probably done it different, right?
A little bit less arrogant, little less, you know, more awareness of
the situation, but he handled the way he handled it.
So God has a plan for him.
And so understand that when God has a plan for you, pressure from
the world and the enemy will be applied because the last thing the enemy
wants for you is for you to live according to God's plan for your life.
Okay.
Well, he's in this pit.
Pressure had begun.
He ended up in Egypt where he became the overseer of Potiphar's house.
God had favor on him, even in the midst of a seemingly terrible situation.
By the way, there's so much to preach here.
I don't have time.
But the situation that you're in, could it be that God's
not going to take you out yet because he wants you to glorify
him during that situation so he can show favor to you
when the world thinks there's no hope in the situation for you.
He shows you favor and all of a sudden you thrive
in that situation, that you really shouldn't thrive in, but you
say to the world that, hey, when I have Jesus, anything is possible,
that's what Joseph did here.
Y'all not with me this morning.
Okay, good.
Thank you, Ms Marty.
I heard you over, everybody.
Oh, me.
So the pressure had begun.
But he was no longer in the pit.
But again, that doesn't mean there's no pressure.
See, according to Genesis 39, verse six, Joseph was a
handsome man in form and appearance.
Now, Joe just shook his head like he can relate to that.
And I don't understand why he did that.
He was like, yeah, that's right, I know.
I know how it is.
So let's think about it for a second.
He is an overseer of a wealthy Egyptian captain.
With basically full access to all of his riches and amenities.
Anyone ever house sat for someone that has a bunch of money?
I did that in high school one time.
We invited all of our friends.
We ate every single bit of their pantry, man.
We even ate the trimming of the pantry.
I'm talking like it was insane.
That was fun, man.
You know what I'm saying?
Like they were like, do whatever you want, eat whatever you want.
We're like, yep, okay.
This is kind of what Joseph had.
Man, this is not the pit anymore.
Like, you're thinking, man, God's having favor on you.
You're in a good situation.
Understand this, pressure comes when you least expect it.
A lot of times pressure can come when you think that everything's good.
Everything's awesome.
Everything's going away, it should go.
See, part of his wife took a liking to this young man.
Remember, he's handsome.
Genesis 39, verse 7, and it came to pass after these things that
his master's wife cast their eyes upon Joseph and
she said, lie with me.
Now I want you to lean into this church.
The world, meow.
The world would call this an opportunity.
Joseph knew it was tribulation.
Joseph did not see this as, 0 man.
What a great opportunity.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
No, no.
He saw this as man, this is pressure from the enemy.
This is opposition.
He would not be found victim of her wicked trap.
Genesis 39, verse 8 and 9, but he refused and said
to his master's wife, Behold with me here, my master
does not concern himself with anything in the house, and he has
put all that he owns in my charge.
There is no one greater in his house than I, and
he has withheld nothing from me.
Look what he said, except for you.
Because you were his wife.
How then?
Could I do this great evil?
And sin against God.
Now notice, he shifts.
The topic of conversation here.
Our master's awesome.
He's given me access to everything except
for you because you're his wife.
But notice he doesn't say that I can't sin against Potiphar.
No, no, no.
He said, how could I do this wicked evil against God?
What a response.
Now, you would think that that would take the pressure off, amen?
Right?
Like shoo shoo, not happening.
Well, that's not what happened.
Genesis, by the way, the devil is
a patient and methodical enemy.
He is committed to the long game, and so ought we be.
Amen?
Last night, anyone like to scare people?
Like to scare people?
Yeah?
No, you don't have to like them.
Ha, ha.
You know, doing that?
Okay, it's a personality flaw in y'all, okay?
So last night, I was trying to scare
my girls, they were up in a bed and it was like, man, they were talking like
little sisters.
And I couldn't really understand what one of them was saying,
but, you know, I kind of, you know, context clues.
But anyway, so I'm going up there and man, I'm dude, I got it on video.
I'm like, I'm sneaking.
I'm talking about this right here.
Anytime it'd be like, little creek, I'd stop because I know.
I've done this before, and they know what's been,
so I was, man, it took me like, I took, took me like several
minutes to get up these stairs.
Then I get right up the stairs and I notice, oh, my shadows right there.
They might be seeing that.
So I had to like stop real quick.
I mean, I wish this could be on video me doing this, not
me videoing from the phone, because I probably looked ridiculous.
And I got up, man, I'm telling you what, man, it was like, it was the right time.
And I went out and I said, And
dude, I'm telling you what, it was the best moment of the whole day, right?
But what I'm trying to say is this.
I had to be patient.
I couldn't just run up the stairs.
Ha!
No, they saw me coming.
Right?
I had to be methodical.
I'd be patient.
Listen the enemy is the same way.
He's not just going to show his hand right out the gate.
Right?
See, Joseph probably thought, man, I handled him.
Like, God, do you hear my response?
I'm not going to sin against you.
So this is all over, but that's not what happened.
The pressure continued.
Genesis 39, verse 10.
And as she spoke to Joseph day after day.
He did not listen to her or lie beside her or be with her.
Now, we do not know exactly how long this lasted.
Now, we can't estimate about how long Joseph was overseeing Potiphar's house.
He was 17 when he was sold into slavery.
We are told he was 30 when we became 2nd in command in Egypt as a whole.
Again, there's a whole nother part of the story.
We're not going to get to today.
If you consider the time in prison,
If you consider the time in a pit somehow or maybe in
between, you know, being sold as in slavery, it
could have spent 10 to 11 years.
He could have been in Potiphar's house for 10 or 11 years.
And the Bible says day by day.
Did part of his wife applies sinful pressure the entire time?
We cannot know for sure.
We just know that it was a daily occurrence and temptation.
And you would think that his obedience to the Lord would have gotten him rewarded.
But to summarize the story, this is what happened.
Finally, one day, She comes to him again, lie with me.
Now, now, everyone knows what that means.
Amen?
She had she has some ill intentions for Joseph.
All right?
It was a sinful, wicked situation.
And instead and finally, he couldn't take it anymore.
He said, no, and he fleed.
He ran away.
He actually physically ran away from
part of his wife to get out of the temptation.
And what happened?
She grabbed his cloak.
Took it off as he was running away.
And because now, hey, the secret's out.
Right?
What are they going to think when they realized, hey, Joseph, why'd you run away?
Because pot of his wife keeps on trying to sleep with me.
And I keep on telling her, no, she couldn't
let that happen, so she lied about it.
Hey, he tried to sleep with me and look, I have his cloak move it,
and he ran away in shame.
Well, guess what happened?
He got thrown into prison.
See, we see scripture, uh, we see scripture in
God's commands fulfilled by Joseph 1000s of years before they were even written.
It doesn't matter the cost of obedience, God,
God wants obedience.
And by the way, obedience is to protect you, not to hurt you.
Proverbs 4, 14 through 15, do not enter the path of the wicked.
and do not proceed in the way of evil men.
Avoid it, do not pass by it, turn away from it and pass on.
That's what he did.
First Corinthians 10, 13, no temptation is overtaken you, but
such as is common to man, and God is faithful, who
will not allow you to be tempted to be on what you are able, but what
the temptation will provide the way of escape also so that
you will be able to endure it.
Hey, that's what Joseph did.
You know what the way escape was?
The door.
He ran out of it.
2nd Timothy 222.
Now flee.
That means to literally run away from youthful lust
and pursue righteousness, faith, love, and peace with those who call
on the Lord from a pure heart.
That's what he did.
James 47.
Submit yourselves, therefore, to God, resist the devil, and he will flee
from you.
Church, we have an enemy who knows how to oppress us.
He knows how to stir the waters trouble in our life.
He knows how to apply the pressure that will most likely
weaken us.
Listen, I know the story of Joseph is a specific kind of impression,
but the principle is the same.
When trouble comes, how do you respond?
Oftentimes stand ground and resisting means getting away
from the temptation and trouble.
You say, what if I can?
What if there's nowhere to run?
How do you find a way of escape when you when you can't seem to find it?
When Paul wrote this commandment of God, he wrote it to the believers in Rome.
And in that time, Rome was the greatest military force the world has ever seen.
I mean, they were conquering other
nation after other nations.
I mean, they were taking over the whole stinking world, man.
They had very specific strategies of resisting attack and holding their ground in the heat of battle.
And some of the some of the greatest strategies in the midst of battle.
Listen to me now, they were not necessarily offensive.
They were defensive.
See, the 3 main defensive formations, let me just give you some ideas here.
First, you had what was called the triple line.
A staggered checkerboard battle arrangement split in
the front, middle, and rear to ensure fresh troops were
always ready to plug gaps.
In other words, they could stand and triple line as long as they needed to.
Then next, what you had was the tortoise.
A specialized type formation where front and side ranks
lock shields vertically, while rear ranks held sheards overhead
to block incoming arrows during advances.
Doesn't matter how many arrows come their way, they're covered.
And then you have one of the most familiar battle formations.
You seen it in movies, you've read it in books, the interlocking shield wall.
Soldiers locked their heavy shields together, creating a continuous
physical barrier that absorbed impact and deflected
enemy missiles.
One of the greatest military forces the world has ever seen could
attribute much of their success to proper defensive formations.
Now don't be wrong, they were good at offense too, but they were legendary.
for not losing ground.
Wow.
Because they know 2 things about battle.
To lose ground was the 1st step in losing the battle.
Christians, it is no different in our spiritual battles we face today.
We cannot afford to lose ground.
I want you to also notice that the success of these formations depended
on the joint effort of each soldier.
If one soldier is out of place, it causes a fracture in the line.
If 2 soldiers are out of place.
It causes a gap in the line.
Several soldiers at a place causes a catastrophic
failure in the line, leaving the rest of the soldiers vulnerable,
and defeat is almost already on its way.
Second in every battle.
There was a supreme commander who gave the order to get information.
And to hold.
Cedar group, I hope you're getting this this morning.
Joshua, let's think about him, leader of the nation of Israel.
Now this guy right here, whereas Moses was a great leader, Joshua is a great conqueror.
Right?
Moses, I mean, he led a bunch of bickering,
griping, complaining, just, oh, kind of people.
right?
But he did it well.
He didn't really conquer anything.
They just kind of walked around the wilderness, you know, having meeting at the meeting at the meeting.
Joshua came and was like, okay, time to go.
Let's defeat Jericho.
You know what I'm saying?
Like, so there's a 2 different leaderships there.
You got Moses, then you got Joshua.
Joshua is awesome.
But look at this.
He was the leader of the nation of Israel.
He met the commander in Joshua chapter 5.
Look at it says.
Now it came about when Joshua was by Jericho.
Then he lifted up his eyes and looked, and behold, a man was standing opposite
him with his sword drawn in his hand and Joshua went to
him and said to him, are you for us?
For our adversaries.
In other words, do you force her against us?
He said, no, rather, I indeed come now.
This is this is the man speaking as
captain of the host of the Lord.
And Joshua fell on his face to the earth and bowed down and said to him, what
has my Lord to say to his servant?
In other words, what would you have me do?
Now Joshua's pretty, pretty good at what he was doing, but
hey, let me just tell you something, when the commander comes in the room, You stop what you're doing.
Lord, what would you have me do?
The same captain, the host of the Lord is called the Word in John one.
So what is our commander instructing us to do?
That is Jesus Christ during the pressure of the daily battle we face as believers?
Well, Romans 12, 12.
He commands us to be rejoicing in hope.
Patient in tribulation.
Now, What does this have to do with us?
Because again, We're not banding together today to
go conquer Mount Juliet.
You know what I'm saying?
That's not happening.
Okay?
We're not hopefully in a situation to
where Joseph was.
So how does that apply to us?
Now, do you remember?
Do you remember at the beginning of the message, 2.5 hours ago, from that?
If you remember, I told everyone to bow your heads, close your eyes, you don't do it again.
And I simply said, if you got anything that's difficult in your life,
that you're trying to deal with right now.
Raise your hand.
And guess what happened?
Most of the room raised their hand.
So what do I do?
I said, hey, everyone, look around.
What I was hoping that would do is open our eyes to the fact that
we're not struggling alone.
We may not be suffering or struggling the exact same way as the
person besides you behind you in front of you, but we are,
but listen, struggle and suffering is struggle and suffering.
And I can attest to you right here, right now today.
I just want you to hear me.
The struggling is hard.
Tuffering is difficult.
When that pressure is applied, you know what it's easy to do?
It's easy to isolate.
It's easy to fall back from the line.
And to do your own thing.
Hear me, church.
That's exactly what the devil wants you to do.
Because see, when you fall back, what you do, you fracture the line.
So now not only are you being hurt.
But now you have created a vulnerable situation for those around you.
Remember, we're a family.
And so as I get tired in my life, I
used to think I could do anything better than anyone in any situation.
I say, I say terms and some of you can, don't amen this.
You just know that's true.
I used to say things like, man, burnout is for losers.
Don't you know who you're serving?
dont get burned out.
And then all of a sudden I get burned out.
And now I'm hurting now.
I don't know what to do.
I don't know where to turn.
The situations that come up in our lives that we just don't.
And so instead of isolating like I have done in the past.
I need my fellow believers.
To help me hold the line.
You can't.
I'm gonna do something here, and I hope I don't embarrass anybody.
David, can you come up here for a second?
Tony, can you come up here for a second?
I picked two.
Just, uh, beast that we have here at Cedar Grove.
Just know if you try to get to me.
You gotta get through to him.
But listen, these are 2 brothers I know that love the Lord.
And I understand this.
I understand that they have, listen, they have struggles.
They have issues.
They have things that are going on.
They have difficult circumstances.
And the devil's after them.
But also, he's after me.
So what does the Bible say?
What does it mean to interlock shields of faith?
Well, listen, if I'm tired and I start to get weary and I start to try
to find something to lean on, I can't, I'm just going to fall.
Get up here so we can see.
Or please, sir.
But look, if I just have right here, we can just interlock right here.
Now, look, I can get tired, I won't.
Man, my family's in shambles.
David, help.
I feel like depression has just overtaken my life.
Man, my children, they're wayward brothers, help me.
I can't, they're not gonna let me go.
Why?
Because we're brothers.
Now guess what?
You can let me go now.
That was serious.
Yeah, I'll go back to your seats.
Thank you.
Now, listen, you say, what about them?
Jacob, you just made that illustration all about you.
Well, I can call in person after person all morning.
to come back up.
And then guess what?
When I become strengthened, when now I can hold the line.
Now, the person on each side of those men, now we can help them hold the line.
Are you with me, Cedar Grove?
What I'm trying to say is this.
We were not meant to suffer alone.
We were not meant.
to fight alone.
So brothers and sisters and fellow soldiers in the army of the Lord.
Rather than isolating ourselves when the times get tough.
Rather together, we resist the enemy.
We refuse to lose ground.
No matter the trouble or pressure he throws our way, we interlock
our shields of faith, why?
Because Ephesians 6, verse 16 talks about this, above all,
taking the shoot of faith, wherewith ye shall be able to quench all the
fiery darts of the wicked.
So as the enemy does his best.
And we start seeing those darts just flying around.
You know what we can believe and rejoice in?
The enemy's best.
doesn't touch our commander,
the Lord Jesus Christ.
We are fighting and already won battle.
Hezban eyes closed over this place.